In this video we're finally gonna come to the technical highlight of bottom up
在这段视频中，我们最终将看到自下而上的技术亮点
parsings After all the definitions of the previous videos now we're actually gonna
解析完之前视频的所有定义，现在我们实际上要
be able to give the algorithm for recognizing viable prefixes. So let's dive
能够给出识别可行前缀的算法。所以让我们潜水吧
straight into the algorithm. The first step is really just a very technical point
直接进入算法。第一步真的只是一个非常技术性的问题
and it's not, not that important. But we're going to do it anyway because it
这不是，也不是那么重要。但不管怎样，我们还是要这么做，因为它
makes things simpler Is to add a dummy production as prime goes to S to our
让事情变得更简单的是添加一个虚拟的产品，因为质数转到S到我们的
grammar of interest G. So, just to set the stage we are trying to compute the viable
感兴趣的语法。所以，为了做好准备，我们尝试计算可行的
prefixes of G. We're trying to come up with a, algorithm for recognizing the
前缀G。我们正试图想出一种算法来识别
viable prefixes of G. If S is the start symbol, we're going to make up a new start
G的可行前缀。如果S是开始符号，我们将组成一个新的开始
symbol as prime, so as prime would be the new start symbol of augmented grammar and
作为素数的符号，因此素数将成为扩充语法的新起点
it's just one production for as prime as prime goes to S. Right. So this just allow
这只是一部素数为S的素数制作的作品。所以这只是允许
us to know exactly where our start symbol is used, in particular our new start
我们要确切地知道我们的开始符号在哪里使用，特别是我们的新开始
symbol as prime is only used in one place and. Left hand side of this one
作为质数的符号只在一个地方使用，并且。这张的左手边
production, and that just makes things a little bit simpler. Now, recall what we
生产，这只会让事情变得简单一点。现在，回想一下我们
are trying to do. We claim that the set of viable prefixes for a given grammar is
都在努力做到这一点。我们认为给定语法的可行前缀集是
regular and so what we're going to do is we're going to construct a
所以我们要做的是，我们要构建一个
non-deterministic final automaton that recognizes the viable prefixes, okay? And
识别可行前缀的非确定性最终自动机，好吗？和
the states of this NFA are going to be the items of the grammar. Now the input to the
这个NFA的状态将是语法的项目。现在，输入到
NFA is the stack. So the NFA reads the stack, okay? And then it, So let's
NFA是堆栈。所以NFA读取堆栈，好吗？然后它，所以让我们
indicate this, so the NFA is gonna take the stack as an argument, and it's either
指出这一点，所以NFA会将堆栈作为参数，它要么
gonna say yes, that's a viable prefix, or no. And it's gonna read the stack from
我会说是，这是个可行的前缀，或者不是。它将从堆栈中读取
bottom to top. So it's gonna start at the bottom of the stack, and read towards the
从下到上。所以它将从堆栈的底部开始，读到
top of the stack. And our goal here is to write a non entromystic finite automaton
堆栈的顶部。我们的目标是编写一个非熵的有限自动机
that recognizes the valid stacks of the purser. So that is how we'll know. That,
来识别事务长的有效堆栈。所以这就是我们知道的方式。那,
our parser hasn't really counted any parse errors. Because this automaton that we're
我们的解析器并没有真正统计出任何解析错误。因为这个机器人，我们是
going to construct will always output e ither yes, this stack is okay, meaning it
要进行构造将始终输出YES，这个堆栈是好的，这意味着它
could wind up, parsing, the input. Or no, what we've got on the stack now, doesn't
可能会结束、解析、输入。或者不，我们现在在堆栈上的东西，不会
resemble any valid stack for any possible parse of any input string for this
类似于对此输入字符串的任何可能解析的任何有效堆栈
grammar. Okay, so let's think about, what we, what we need the moves of this machine
语法。好的，那么让我们想一想，我们需要什么，我们需要这台机器的动作
to be. So let's say that we're in the state E, arrow, alpha dot X beta. Now,
成为。假设我们处于状态E，箭头，α点Xβ。现在,
what does that say? So that says that so far, we've seen alpha on the stack. Okay,
上面写的是什么？也就是说，到目前为止，我们已经看到了堆栈上的α。好吧,
so remember the machine is reading the stack from bottom to top. This records the
所以请记住，机器是从下到上读取堆栈的。这记录了
fact that the machine has already seen 'quot;alpha'quot; on the stack. So, what would be an
事实上，机器已经在堆栈上看到了‘alpha’。那么，
okay thing to see next on the stack? Well, if this is a valid stack, if having
堆栈上的下一个要看的是什么？如果这是一个有效的堆栈，如果有
'quot;alpha'quot; on the stack at this point is valid, well then certainly it would be
堆栈上的‘alpha’在这一点上是有效的，那么它肯定是有效的
okay if the next thing on the stack was an 'quot;X.'quot; So, we have a transition that if
好的，如果堆栈上的下一件事是“X”，那么我们有一个转换，如果
we're in this state Where we are working on this production, and we've seen alpha
我们在这个州，我们正在制作这部作品，我们已经看到了阿尔法
on the stack. If the next thing is an X on input X, then we can go to this state.
在堆栈上。如果下一件事是输入X上的X，那么我们可以进入这种状态。
Where now we record the fact that we've seen alpha X on the stack, and we're
现在我们记录我们在堆栈上看到αX的事实，我们是
waiting to see, the remaining portion, beta, of that production. Okay, so this is
我们拭目以待，那部作品的剩余部分，测试版。好的，这就是
one kind of move that the non triamistic phymotine can make, and again, we do, we
一种非三位一体的植物体可以做的动作，我们又一次做了，我们
add this kind of a move for every item. So for every item in the grammar, I, if it,
每件商品都要加这样的动作。所以对于语法中的每一项，我，如果它，
if the dot is not all the way at the right end, then there will be a move like this
如果圆点不是一直在正确的一端，那么就会有这样的移动
where the dot moves over, for whatever symbol happens to come to the right of the
点移动的位置，因为任何符号恰好位于
dot. The other class of transitions are the following And these are the, the more
多特。另一类转换如下所示，这些是、更多
interesting ones. So let's say that we're in this, configuration here. Where again,
有趣的事。让我们假设我们在这个构型中。再说一遍，
we've seen alpha. And then the next thing on the stack is X. And here, X is a non
我们见过阿尔法。然后堆栈上的下一项是X。在这里，X是一个非
terminal. [sound]. And I should have said that in the previous case. X was either a
终点站。[声音]。在之前的案例中我应该这么说的。X要么是一个
terminal or a non terminal. So this X here is any grammar symbol, not just a non
终端或非终端。所以这里的X是任何语法符号，而不仅仅是非
terminal. But this, #four here, the, the moves here in part four are specifically
终点站。但是这个，这里的第四个，第四部分这里的动作是特别的
for non terminals. Okay, so anyway, if, X is not on the stack. Okay, let's assume
用于非终端。好的，不管怎样，如果X不在堆栈上。好的，让我们假设
that we've seen alpha, and then the next thing on the stack is not S. Well, is it
我们已经看到了阿尔法，然后堆栈上的下一个东西不是S。嗯，是吗？
possible that there could be a valid configuration of the parser where we saw
可能存在我们看到的解析器的有效配置
alpha but then X didn't appear next? And, the answer is yes because as we said
但是然后X没有出现在下一个？答案是肯定的，因为正如我们所说的
before, the stack is a sequence of partial right hand sides. So it could be that all
在此之前，堆栈是部分右侧的序列。所以可能就是这样
that's on the stack right now for this production. Is alpha and if the next thing
这就是现在这部作品要做的事情。是阿尔法，如果下一件事
on the stack is eventually going to reduce to X. It might not be X itself, it might
最终将减少到X。它可能不是X本身，它可能
be something that will eventually reduce to X. Well, what does that mean? Well,
最终会化为X的东西。嗯，那是什么意思？井,
that means that whatever is there on the stack has to be derived from X, it has to
这意味着堆栈上的任何内容都必须从X派生，它必须
be something that can be Generated by using a sequence of X productions, 'cause
是可以通过使用一系列X产品来生成的东西，因为
eventually it's going to reduce the X. So for every item that looks like this, and
最终它会降低X，所以对于每一件看起来像这样的东西，
for every production for X now we're going to add the following move, we're going to
现在，对于X的每一次生产，我们将添加以下移动，我们将
say that if there's no X on the stack, well then, we can make an epsilon move, we
假设堆栈上没有X，那么，我们可以进行ε移动，我们
can just shift to a state where we try to recognize the right hand side plus
可以直接转换到这样一种状态，在这种状态下，我们试图识别右手边的加号
something derived from X. And these are the only two kinds of moves Either the
从X派生的东西。这是唯一的两种动作
items, eith sorry, either the grammar symbols we're looking for are there on the
很抱歉，我们要找的语法符号要么在
stack and we extend. >> The prefix of a right hand side. So this rule here extends
堆栈，我们扩展。>>右手边的前缀。所以这条规则在这里延伸了
a prefix. So as we see more of that production on the stack or, it tries to
前缀。因此，当我们在堆栈上看到更多产品时，它会尝试
guess or tries to discover where the ends of the prefixes are. So if, if alpha's as
猜测或尝试找出前缀的末尾在哪里。所以如果，如果阿尔法作为
much of the production that is on the stack currently, well then this must be,
目前堆栈上的大部分产品，那么这肯定是，
this x here must this, this point here must mark the start of another right hand
这里的x必须是这个，这里的这个点一定标志着另一只右手的开始。
side in our stack of right hand sides. So we would expect to see something derived
在我们的右手边堆叠中的一边。所以我们希望看到一些衍生出来的东西
from some production for x. Two more rules. Every state in this automaton is
从x的一些制作中得到的。还有两条规则。这个自动机中的每个状态都是
going to be an accepting state. That means that if the automaton manages to
将会是一个可以接受的状态。这意味着如果自动机设法
successfully consume the entire stack, then the then the stack is viable. And
成功消耗整个堆栈，则堆栈是可行的。和
just notice that not every state is going to have transition on every possibl e,
请注意，并不是每个州都会在所有可能的情况下进行过渡，
symbol. So there will be plenty of possible stacks that, that are rejected
符号。所以会有很多可能的堆栈被拒绝
simply because the automaton gets stuck. And finally, the start state of this
很简单，因为机器人卡住了。最后，这个开始的状态
automaton is the item as prime goes to dot S. So remember, the states of the machine
自动机是质数转到点s时的项目。所以记住，机器的状态
are the items of the grammar. And this is why we added, this, dummy production, is
是文法中的项目。这就是为什么我们增加了，这个，虚拟制作，是
just so that we could conveniently name the start state. So now, let's consider,
这样我们就可以方便地命名开始状态。所以现在，让我们考虑一下，
one of our, grammars we've been using a lot, so this is the grammar. And now we're
这是我们经常使用的语法之一，所以这就是语法。现在我们是
going to augment it, with the extra production as prime goes to E. And let's
为了增加它，将额外的产量作为质数分配给E，让我们
take a look at the automaton for that recognizes the viable prefixes of this
让我们看一下的自动机，它可以识别以下内容的可行前缀
grammar. And here it is, and as you can see, it's rather large it has a lot of
语法。这就是，正如你所看到的，它相当大，有很多
states and a lot of transitions, and I just want to show it to you here before we
状态和很多过渡，我只想在我们开始之前展示给你们看
describe how we calculated it, just so you can get an idea that these [inaudible] for
描述一下我们是如何计算出来的，这样你就可以知道这些(听不见的)
recognizing viable prefixes for grammars are actually quite elaborate. But, now
识别语法的可行前缀实际上相当复杂。但是，现在
let's break this down and see how it was produced. So, let's begin with the start
让我们把它分解一下，看看它是如何制作的。那么，让我们从开始说起
state of this machine, so we have S prime goes to dot E. And, remember what this
这台机器的状态，所以我们有S一撇转到点E，记住这是什么
says is we want to be able to reduced to the start symbol to the new start symbol.
就是说我们要能够把开始符号降到新的开始符号。
And so we're reading the stack, and we're hoping to see an E on the stack, and if we
所以我们正在读取堆栈，我们希望在堆栈上看到一个E，如果我们
don't then we're happy to see something derived from E. So, what transition we
不是吗？我们很高兴看到E派生出一些东西。那么，我们的过渡是什么呢？
make from the state. One possibility is that we do in fact see an eon a stack, and
从州里弄来的。一种可能性是，我们确实看到了一个堆叠的Eon，并且
in that case the dot simply moves over saying yes we've read the first item on
在这种情况下，圆点只是移到前面说，是的，我们已经阅读了上面的第一条
the stack or the, we've read the E on the stack and so we've seen the full right
堆栈或，我们已经读取了堆栈上的E，所以我们看到了完整的权利
hand side of this production. Now that would indicate that we were probably done
这部作品的另一面。现在这表明我们很可能已经完成了
with parsing. This is the state that you would reach, have you'd read the entire
通过解析。这就是你会达到的境界，你有没有读过完整的
input and successfully parsed it, you would have reduced the old start symbol
输入并成功解析它，您就会减少旧的开始符号
and be about to reduce to the augmented the, the new start symbol. But if you're
并即将缩减为增加的，新的开始符号。但如果你
not so fortunate as to see an E on the stack, then you need to hope that you'll
没有那么幸运地看到堆栈上有一个E，那么您需要希望您将
see something derive fro m E. And there are a couple of possibilities there. One
我们可以看到一些东西是从mE中衍生出来的，有几种可能性。一
is that we could see something that would eventually use this production, E goes to
我们可以看到一些最终会用到这部作品的东西，E转到
T. And since we haven't seen any of it yet, we put the dot all the way at the
因为我们还没有看到任何东西，所以我们把圆点一直放在
left, indicating that we're hoping to see a T, which could then reduce to E, and
左边，表示我们希望看到一个T，然后它可能会减少到E，并且
which could then reduce to S prime. Now if we don't see a T on the stack by itself
然后可能会降到S素数。现在，如果我们在堆栈上没有看到T本身
the other possibility is that we could be working on this production. E goes to, T
另一种可能性是我们可能正在制作这部作品。E转到，T转到
plus E. And again, we haven't seen any of it, so the dot Goes on the left hand side.
再说一次，我们没有见过任何东西，所以这个点在左手边。
And then notice how we're crucially using the power of nondeterministic automata. So
然后注意我们是如何关键地使用非确定自动机的力量的。所以
here we don't know which production is going to, which right hand side of a
在这里，我们不知道哪部影片将会上映，一部影片的右手边是哪一部
production is going to appear on the stack. And in fact, I notice that these
生产将会出现在堆栈上。事实上，我注意到这些
productions are not even left factored, so we don't know whether it's going to be
产量甚至没有被考虑在内，所以我们不知道它是否会
just a T there or a T plus E, but. We just use the guessing power of the [inaudible]
那里只有T或者T加E，但是。我们只是利用[听不见的]的猜测能力
chromatin you chose which one to, to use. Remember the [inaudible] sepse is any
染色质你选择用哪一种。记住[听不见的]脓液是任何
possible choice except. So you can always guess correctly. So intuitively you can.
可能的选择除了。所以你总能猜对。所以直觉上你可以。
You will be able to pick the right one. Now of course we could compile this down
你会选对的。现在，我们当然可以把这个汇编下来
to a deterministic machine that won't have to make any guesses. But at this level
一台不需要进行任何猜测的确定性机器。但在这个层面上
we're writing [inaudible] it's extremely useful not to have to figure out which of
我们在写[听不见]不用弄清楚是哪一种是非常有用的
these two productions to use. We can just try both and see what happens. Now let's
这两部作品都要用。我们可以两种都试一试，看看会发生什么。现在让我们
focus on this, state, E goes to dot T. What are the possibilities there? Well,
关注这一点，状态，E是点T，有什么可能性呢？井,
one possibility is that we see a T on the stack. And then we see in a complete right
一种可能性是我们在堆栈上看到T。然后我们看到在一个完全正确的位置
hand side. And notice how when the dot was all the way to the right hand side, that
手边。注意当圆点一直位于右手边时，
is going to indicate that we're ready to do a reduce. So we'll talk about that a
将表明我们已经准备好进行减量。所以我们会讨论这件事
little bit later, but essentially that's how we're going to recognize handles. When
稍晚一点，但本质上这就是我们识别句柄的方式。什么时候
we finally reach a state where the dot is all the way to the right hand side that's
我们最终到达了这样一种状态，即圆点一直在右手边，也就是
going to say this could be a handle that you might want to reduce. Now if we don't
我想说这可能是您想要减小的句柄。现在如果我们不
see a T on the stack , then we just see something derived from T, and there's a
在堆栈上看到一个T，然后我们看到一些从T派生出来的东西，还有一个
couple of possibilities, a few possibilities there. One possibility is
有几种可能性，有几种可能性。一种可能性是
that it's going to be the production T goes to int, so since we're just starting
这将是产品T转到INT，所以既然我们才刚刚开始
on this production again, we just put the dot all the way at the left. Another
在这部作品中，我们只是把圆点一直放在左边。另一个
possibility we're working on T goes to (E). And the third possibility that we're
我们在研究T的可能性是(E)。第三种可能性是我们
working on T goes to int x T. And each of the case here, notice that the dots are
对T的运算为int x T。这里的每个例子，请注意，点是
all the way at the left indicating that we're just getting started, we have not
一直走在左边，表明我们才刚刚开始，我们还没有
actually seen any of the right hand side yet. Now let's shift our focus to this
实际上还没见过右手边的任何人。现在让我们把焦点转移到这个
production, E goes to, dot T plus E. This item, excuse me One possibility is that we
生产，E去，T点加E。这个项目，打扰一下，一种可能是我们
see an E on the see a T on the stack, okay, in which case the dot just moves
在堆栈上看到E，在堆栈上看到T，在这种情况下，点只是移动
over. And the other possibility is that we see something derived from T, in which
完毕。另一种可能性是我们看到一些从T派生出来的东西，其中
case we will go to one of the states that begins a T production. And notice here
万一我们要去一个开始T生产的州。注意这里
that we already have all three of those items in our automaton. We're just going
我们的机器人里已经有了这三样东西。我们要走了
to it states that we went to from the item E goes to dot T. So this, this item, E
表示我们从项目E转到了点T。所以这个，这个项目，E
goes to dot T plus E, could also move to those three states. Now let's focus on
移到T加E点，也可以移到这三个态。现在我们来关注一下
this, item here. T goes to dot, open-paren, E closed-paren. Well, there's
这个，这里的项目。T转到点，开-Paren，E-Closed-Paren。嗯，这里有
only one possible move here, so this is only a, a terminal, it's not, it's not a
这里只有一个可能的动作，所以这只是一个，一个终端，不是，不是
non-terminal, so there's not going to be any possibility of having something
非终结性的，所以不会有任何的可能性
derived from open-paren. We just have to see the open-paren in the input. So
从开帕伦派生出来的。我们只需看到输入中的开放参数。所以
there's only one possible transition here, which is that we see, the open-paren,
这里只有一个可能的过渡，那就是我们看到，开放的帕伦，
excuse me, on the stack, and the dot just moves over. Now, from this state, once
打扰一下，在堆叠上，圆点刚刚移了过来。现在，从这个州，曾经
again, we got is just next to a, or just to the left of a non-terminal, so we might
同样，我们得到的就在a旁边，或者就在非终结符的左边，所以我们可能
see that non-terminal on the stack or we might see something derived from that
看到堆栈上的非终端，或者我们可能会看到从该堆栈派生的内容
non-terminal. Well, if we see that non-terminal on the stack, your dot just
非终端。嗯，如果我们看到堆栈上的非终结符，您的圆点
moves over and we get T(E.) indicating that we've seen an both an ( and E on the
移过去，我们得到T(E)。表示我们在
stack and we're still waiting to see the ). Well we might also see somethin g
堆栈，我们还在等着看)。嗯，我们可能还会看到一些
derived from e, okay. So we add these two transitions to the two items that begin
从e派生出来的，好的。因此，我们将这两个转换添加到开始的两个项目中
productions for e. [sound]. Alright, now, let's focus on this state. T goes to open
为e.[声音]制作的作品。好了，现在让我们来关注一下这个状态。%t去开业
paren E dot closed paren. Again, 'cause it's a terminal, that the dot it's next to
E点闭合的Paren。再说一次，因为它是一个终端，它旁边的圆点
is only one possible move. We have to see that open paren if we see anything at all.
这只是一种可能的举动。如果我们看到什么的话，我们必须去看看那个敞开的帕伦。
And we'll wind up with the item T goes to open paren E, closed paren dot. And now
最后我们会看到项目T去打开Paren E，闭合的Paren点。而现在
we've recognized the entire right hand side of that production on the stack.
我们已经认出了堆栈上那部作品的整个右手边。
Let's take a look at this, item. So we're here, because a terminal symbol, the, only
我们来看看这个，项目。所以我们在这里，因为一个终端符号，唯一的
possibility is to read that terminal symbol on the stack. So this would be the
可能是读取堆栈上的终端符号。所以这将是
next item. E goes to T plus dot E. [sound]. Focusing on that item again
下一件。E转到T加点E[发音]。再次把注意力放在那个项目上
[inaudible] we could possible see an E on the stack. Right, in which case we would
[听不见]我们可以在堆叠上看到一个E。对，那样的话我们就
have recognized the entire writing inside of this production, We have E goes T+E. Or
已经认出了这部作品里面的全部文字，我们有E去T+E，或者说是E去T+E。
we can see something derived from here, which case we make a transition back to
我们可以从这里看到一些东西，在这种情况下，我们可以转换回
one of those two states. Now, where we got productions left to go, or items left to
这两个州中的一个。现在，我们还有作品要去的地方，或者剩下的项目要去的地方
go Here, we haw T goes to.int. So, we would have to see it next on to stack, and
到这儿去，我们要去的地方是.int。因此，我们将不得不在下一个堆栈中看到它，并且
that would be the full right hand side of that production. Down here, we still have
那将是那部作品的全部右手边。在这下面，我们还有
T goes to dot [inaudible] times T. So again, there's a terminal symbol here
转到点[听不见]倍，所以这里又有一个终端符号
[inaudible]. And so that would be the next thing we would need to see on the stack
[听不见]。因此，这将是我们需要在堆栈上看到的下一件事
for this production to remain viable. And once we've seen the [inaudible] we would
才能让这部作品继续存在。一旦我们看到[听不见的]我们就会
like to see the times. So we wind up in this state and now we've got dot next to
我喜欢看“泰晤士报”。所以我们最终来到了这个州，现在我们在旁边有一个圆点
T. So, again, one possibility is that we see the T on the stack and then we've seen
再说一次，一种可能是我们看到堆栈上的T，然后我们看到
the full right-hand side of this production. But we might only see
这部作品的全部右手边。但我们可能只能看到
something derive from T. The might, the, the T might not be there yet. It might be
从T派生出的一些东西，可能还没有到那个地步，那个T可能还没有到那里。可能是因为
in a state where we're still waiting for the T to appear through some sequence of
在我们仍在等待T通过某个序列出现的状态下
reductions. But then we would need to see something derive from T. And in this case
减价。但是我们需要看到一些从T派生出来的东西，在这种情况下
we would make a transition to one of the three states that begin the productions
我们将过渡到开始制作的三个州之一
for T. And that 's the full automaton. That is, those are all the states and all
对于T来说，这就是完整的自动机。也就是说，这些就是所有的状态和所有的状态。
the transitions for the automaton that recognizes the viable prefixes of this grammar.
识别此语法的可行前缀的自动机的转换。